canterbury.ac.uk 2019-09-23

# CCCU Cookies Privacy Notice

## General

  * This Policy explains what types of personal information will be gathered when you visit the Website of Canterbury Christ Church University ("the University"), and how this information will be used. Although this Website provides links to other websites, this policy applies only to the University's Webpages.
  * The University has a commitment to protecting your privacy and respecting the confidentiality of information you provide when you visit the University's Websites at either 'canterbury.ac.uk' or 'cant.ac.uk'. At the same time, the University seeks to ensure that you obtain value from the Website and from the services that you may want to receive.
  * The University is registered as a data controller under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and Data Protection Act 2018 ('the 2018 Act'). The University upholds the relevant data protection principles and processes all personally identifiable information about you ("personal data") in accordance with the GDPR and the 2018 Act and other relevant legislation. This Privacy Policy explains what information we may collect about you when you visit the University's Website and how we may use it.
  * You should read this Privacy Policy in conjunction with the University's Website terms and conditions of use, of which this Privacy Policy forms a part. By agreeing to these terms and conditions, you are consenting to the University's processing of your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. The University will post any changes to this Privacy Policy on the University's Website.

## Information collected

  * It is possible to use the University's Website without providing any personal data. However, the University may automatically collect certain information about you when you use the Website, including by using “cookies” (see below), such as the Internet Protocol (IP) address of your computer and the dates and times of your visits.
  * In some areas of the University's Website you may be asked for personal data, such as your name, address and e-mail details, to make your site visit a more rewarding experience for you or to contact you afterwards. This might be where you complete an online form requesting a copy of a prospectus, book a place on an open day, request information about a job vacancy, or subscribe to an online newsletter.
  * In some other areas of the University's Website, where you can register as an online user, you may need to supply further personal data.

## Use of information collected

  * The University holds and processes personal data collected about you through the University's Website by using University computers and computing systems. The University retains this data for a reasonable period or for as long as the law requires.
  * The University will not disclose any of your personal data collected to any third party, unless required to do so by law, other than in circumstances set out in this policy. There may be circumstances in which the University asks you to agree to the disclosing of your personal data to certain third parties, or transferring it outside the United Kingdom. However, before transferring your personal data in these circumstances, the University will seek to ensure appropriate arrangements are in place to protect your privacy.
  * The University may use personal data collected from you by means of the University's Website to manage and monitor use of the Website. Otherwise, the University will only use personal data for the purposes for which it was collected, unless you gave consent to use it for other stated purposes. For example, if you supply your name and address so the University can send you a prospectus, and, at the same time, you agree we may send you similar information in the future, we may subsequently invite you to an open day.
  * If at any time you want to withdraw any permission you have given us to provide you with services, or to use your personal data in any other way, you can do so by [contacting the Data Protection Officer](mailto:foi@canterbury.ac.uk "email foi@canterbury.ac.uk").

## Cookies

  * When you visit the University's Website, your computer may be issued with a small file (a "cookie") for the purposes of managing and improving the services on the Website, even if you do not provide us with any personal data. Cookies recognise you, by a unique number allocated to you, when you return to the Website and may personalise your return, for example by customising Webpages based on areas of the Website that were previously of interest to you. If you previously provided personal data, then cookies may enable the automatic completion of your name and other information when, for example, you complete an online form.
  * Cookies also enable the University to compile anonymous, aggregated statistics to help understand how the Website is used, and so how to make improvements. It is not possible for cookies to read personal information on your computer or to find out any personal information about you. You can refuse to accept cookies by modifying the settings in your browser, but this may limit the functionality of Webpages on, or your access to, the Website.
  * There are two types of cookie that you may encounter when using the University's website.

### First party cookies

First party cookies: these are our own cookies, set and controlled by us.

Name| Purpose  
---|---  
ASP.NET_SessionId, ASPSESSIONIDASQQQTQC | These session cookies can be used to remember any page changes or item or data selection from page to page.  
  
### Third party cookies

Third party cookies: these are cookies found in other companies’ internet tools which we are using to enhance our site, for example Google Analytics and YouTube have their own cookies, which are controlled by them. On the University's website these include:

Name| Purpose| More info  
---|---|---  
Cookies with names prefixed by __utm | Stores information used by Google Analytics to track user activity on the site. | [ Policy ](https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies "view site www./developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies") | [ Opt-out ](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/ "view site www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/")  
_atuvc, _atshc, bt, di, dt, loc, psc, ssc, ssh, sshs, uid, uvc, uit | Stores information used by AddThis to integrate social media functionality on the site, such as Facebook and Twitter sharing. | [ Policy ](http://www.addthis.com/privacy "visit visit www.addthis.com/privacy") | [ Opt-out ](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out "visit site www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out")  
demographics, VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE, dkv, HSID, SSID, use_hitbox, SID, ACTIVITY, PREF | Used by the YouTube video hosting service to enable videos to be embedded in the site. |    
  
You can find out more about cookies at  [ www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "visit site  www.allaboutcookies.org"), or if you wish to opt out of vendor's use of cookies for interest based advertising, visit [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/ "Your Online Choices")

## Subject Access Requests

  * Under the GDPR, you have the right to know if the University holds any personal data about you. If the University holds any personal data about you, you are entitled to a description of the data, to be told for what purposes the data are processed, and the people, or classes of people, to whom the data may have been disclosed.
  * A request for a copy of information held about you is a “Subject Access Request”. To make a subject access request, you should [contact the Data Protection Officer. ](mailto:foi@canterbury.ac.uk "email foi@canterbury.ac.uk")
  * The University is entitled to, and does, charge a fee for providing this information.

## Security

  * This Website, and the University's computer systems, has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of personal data.

## Other Websites

  * This Website may contain links to other Websites outside the University's control not covered by this privacy policy. The University is not responsible for the contents or reliability of the linked Websites and does not necessarily endorse the views expressed within them. Listing should not be taken as endorsement of any kind. There is no guarantee these links will work all of the time and there is no control over the availability of the linked pages. The University takes no responsible for the privacy policies of any linked Websites.

### The Data Protection Officer

Contact details are as follows

**Robert Melville  
** **Assistant University Secretary** Canterbury Christ Church University **  
**Rochester House  
St George’s Place  
Canterbury  
CT1 1UT

Website:  [https://www.canterbury.ac.uk  
](https://www.canterbury.ac.uk/)Contact details: dp.officer@canterbury.ac.uk

Further information about how CCCU processes personal data and your rights related to it, is in our  [Data Protection Policy](https://www.canterbury.ac.uk/university-solicitors-office/policies-and-procedures/data-protection.aspx "Data protection").
